Guide to the Thaddeus Sheldon Papers on Harmonia, 1853-1868 DAR.1960.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Thaddeus Sheldon Papers on Harmonia
1853-1868
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Sheldon, Thaddeus S.
Spear, John Murray
DAR.1960.01
1.67 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
The nineteenth century utopian community of Harmonia, located in the valley of Kiantone Creek, straddling both New York and Pennsylvania, was known variously as Harmonia, the Association of Beneficents, The Sacred Order of Unionists, or The Domain. This collection consists mostly of letters, speeches, meeting minutes, financial statements of the Harmonia organization, and papers on various subjects such as education, the future of America, and sacred matrimony, which were frequently delivered as addresses to the group. Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Biography
The nineteenth century utopian community of Harmonia, located in the valley of Kiantone Creek, situated on the border between New York and Pennsylvania, was known variously as Harmonia, the Association of Beneficents, The Sacred Order of Unionists, and The Domain. This group of spiritualists "believed that the great men and women of earlier ages were guiding them toward the realization of a new social order. Some of their ideas included a perpetual motion machine, the curing of disease by 'magnetic waters,' world federalism, feminine emancipation, marriage reform, and the manufacture of sewing machines." The leader of the Kiantone Harmonia was John Murray Spear, a Universalist minister, and later, a spiritualist.
Harmonia was interested in practical ideas as well as idealistic plans for a utopian world with reforms in government, education, business, and marriage. Views on education, for example, describe a progressive theory which recommends the use of field trips and laboratory experiments, and advocates the education of women on an equal basis with men.
Spear, a staunch abolitionist, and members of the Harmonia community undertook a river voyage to New Orleans on the Cleopatra in a plan to secure recruits for the association. The trip was also a peace mission to protest the outbreak of a civil war in 1859 and 1860.
Members were also involved in the following sewing machine companies: Orvis, Boyd and Co.; Orvis and Williams Co.; the New York, Boston and Philadelphia Sewing Machine Embroidering Co.; and the American Sewing and Embroidery Machine Company.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection consists mostly of correspondence; speeches; meeting minutes and financial statements of the Harmonia organization, and papers on various subjects such as education, the future of America, and sacred matrimony (frequently delivered as addresses to the group). These papers document the activities of a mid-nineteenth century utopian group which combined its philosophy, socialism, and ideas about spiritualism.
Many of the documents are addresses and essays written by Spiritualist John Murray Spear (1804-1887) on a wide range of topics, such as education, human relations, and government. Some of Spear's correspondence is also part of the collection. Other important members of the group whose letters and papers are part of the collection include Daniel and Rebecca H. Gano, John Orvis, and Thaddeus S. Sheldon, who received custody of the papers upon the dissolution of Harmonia. Many of the communications and speeches were transcribed or rewritten by Caroline Hinkley, who was the Scribe, or secretary, of the Order. Hinckley, a woman's rights advocate, began a relationship with the then married Spear and gave birth to their child in 1859. In 1863 Spear divorced his wife of thirty-two years in order to marry Hinckley and legitimize their son.
Several of the papers, as well as letters, written in 1863, decry the institution of slavery and question whether the Civil War could force a union based on freedom. Additionally, scattered papers from 1861 through 1865 reveal the group's interest in perfecting and selling sewing machines.
Also of note are the signatures on a number of items. The "signatures" of John Quincy Adams and Benjamin Franklin appear on several documents, possibly reflecting the personas of J. M. Spears or Thaddeus Stephens who adopted Franklin and Adams, respectively, as their guides from the past. Please note these are not the actual signatures of Adams, Franklin, or other notable figures that had long since been deceased.
In the contents list, if the title of an essay is not accompanied by a name, the author is unknown. In some cases, although an author has not been identified on the document, if the author is presumed to be known, their name is indicated in [brackets]. Additionally, if a date is not specified but believed to be known, it is identified by the use of the "ca." abbreviation.
Series II of the papers contains twenty-six folders of correspondence concerning the community which were written and received by Mr. Ernest C. Miller, the donor of this collection. There are also research notes relating to Harmonia at Kiantone.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into two series in chronological order. In Series I, items in Box 4 had previously been cataloged separately, but were later combined. At some point in the past they were identified and sorted by year and this arrangement has been maintained.
Series I. Harmonia documents
Series II. Ernest C. Miller Correspondence and Research
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ernest C. Miller to the Darlington Memorial Library in 1960.
Previous Citation
Thaddeus Sheldon Papers on Harmonia, 1853-1868, DAR.1960.01, Darlington Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
This collection has been previously cited as: DAR#2.
Custodial History
This collection was located in the Darlington Memorial Library in the University's Cathedral of Learning until 2007 when it was moved to the ULS Archives Service Center for processing, storage, preservation and service. However, it remains in the custodianship of the ULS Special Collections Department.
Communities -- New York (State) -- Kiantone; Minutes (Administrative records); Speeches; Financial records; Correspondence; Kiantone (N.Y.); Sewing-machine industry -- United States -- History; Spiritualists -- United States; American Sewing and Embroidery Machine Company; New York, Boston and Philadelphia Sewing Machine Embroidering Company; Spear, John Murray; Miller, Ernest C.; Hinckley, Caroline; Buffum, Jonathan; Orvis, John; Gano, Daniel; Sterling, John; Harmonia Community; Orvis, Boyd and Company; Orvis and Williams Company; Sheldon, Thaddeus S.
- Harmonia documents, I.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains items created by members of the Harmonia community and documents the organizations beliefs and codes of conduct.
  - "There is a Law of Love," by T. S. Sheldon, April 8, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, by J. M. Spear, April 12, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Of the Masculine and Feminine Principles as Exhibited in the Mineral, Vegetable and Animal Kingdoms," by T. S. Sheldon, February 8, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Of the Relation Which Man Bears to the Mineral, Vegetable and Animal Kingdoms," by J. M. Spear, February 8, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Address to Mr. Treadwell, by J. M. Spear, March 1857 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Untitled, by J. M. Spear, April 21, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Of Growth or Expansions," by J. M. Spear, May 31, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Of the Whole Subject of Reproduction As It Relates to the Mineral, Vegetable and Animal Worlds," by J. M. Spear, July 10, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Of Education," by J. M. Spear, December 8, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Human Chemistry-What is It?," by J. M. Spear, September 24, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Thomas Richmond to Honorable N. P. Tallmadge, November 14, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Of Government," by J. M. Spear, November 19, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Thomas Richmond to J. M. Spear, December 13, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Daniel Gano to T. S. Sheldon, December 29, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Address of Mrs. Peabody to J. M. Spear, January 19, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Address of Mrs. Peabody to J. M. Spear, second session, January 20, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Of Bread Making," by J. M. Spear, March 1859 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Eliza J. Kenny to John Orvis, April 1859 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Basis of Temporary Union and Rules to be Observed by the Laborers and Dwellers on the Homeville Domain, August 20, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Journal titled "Humanity's Book", August 22, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Notice signed John Quincy Adams, September 7, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Questions to be Answered by the Educationist," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], September 12, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - J. M. Spear to G. F. Lewis, October 9, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - J. M. Spear to Dr. Atkinson, October 25, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Untitled, November 11, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "To the Pilot," by J. M. Spear, December 2, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Of Labors of the Aggregationist, Constructor and Pilot at Pittsburg, etc., December 4, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "To the Constructor,"December 9, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "To the Provisionist," [J. M. Spear], December 22, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "To the Leaderess," [J. M. Spear], December 22, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "To the Pilot," [J. M. Spear], December 27, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Untitled, [J. M. Spear], December 27, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Communications received since starting on the river expedition, by J. M. Spear, October 12, 1859-February 23, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "To the Pilot,"January 7, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "From 'Fidelity' to the 'Leaderess',"January 7, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Apostles of the General Assembly in the Spirit Life, January 19, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "The Universal Congress on this Planet," by L. Judd Pardee, January 20, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Untitled, by J. M. Spear, January 22, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Untitled, by J. M. Spear, January 23, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Sources of Contribution to Aid and Assist the Sacred Order" and "Of the Center and Sub Centers," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], January 29, 1860 and January 30, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Rules to be Observed by the Leading Mind of the General Assembly, February 16, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Pledge of Secrecy to the Sacred Order of Unionists, February 23, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Papers transmitted during the river journey by J. M. Spear, February 26, 1860-June 6, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Letter of introduction for Spear and Hinckley by Daniel Gano, March 5, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "Of Things to be Done at Cuba and its Adjuncts," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], May 5, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "To the Omniarch," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], May 7, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Deed, George W. Mordecai to Alpheus Cowles, April 10, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "Of the Electric Motor" [J. M. Spear], June 2, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Copy of report of river expedition, etc., to "My Brother and Colaborer" [T. S. Sheldon], July 1, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Outline of plans and purposes of the Sacred Order and Of Symbols for the Sacred Order, July 27 and 28, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "To the Apostle of Harmony," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], September 3, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Daniel Gano to T. S. Sheldon, September 5, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - John M. Spear to Thaddeus Sheldon, October 17, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - "Of Manuscripts," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], October 19, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - "Of the Laws of Trade," [J. M. Spear], [January 1], 1861 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - "My Sister" Address, by J. M. Spear, August 1, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Address to the Assembly, by J. M. Spear, August 22, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - "Thanksgiving and Prayer," by J. M. Spear, September 16, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Compact on the part of Thaddeus S. Sheldon and Horace Fenton, drawn up by Spear, January 1, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Contract between Thaddeus S. Sheldon and Mary Gardner, drawn up by Spear, January 1, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Purposes of the Spirit Association for the Year 1861, by J. M. Spear (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Of the True Apostles of the General Assembly," [T. S. Sheldon], March 8, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Program of Things To Be Done in the Old World," [T. S. Sheldon], March 18, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Untitled, March 19, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Disclosure," by J. M. Spear, March 21, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Of Speculation," [T. S. Sheldon], March 22, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Of Transistions," [T. S. Sheldon], March 22, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Of Concentration and Construction," by J. M. Spear, March 28, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Of Machines and Inventions in General and of the Sewing Machine in Special" and "Personal Preparations for Constructive Labors," by J. M. Spear, April 1, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Preliminaries," by J. M. Spear, April 1, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Of Inherency," by J. M. Spear, April 2, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Of Reciprocity," by J. M. Spear, April 2, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Of Methods," by J. M. Spear, April 2, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Of the Order of an Unfolding," by J. M. Spear, April 3, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Elucidation," by J. M. Spear, April 4, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Programme of Labors at the Implementist's Shop," by J. M. Spear, April 5, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Order Of Procedure," by J. M. Spear, April 5, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Of Power," by J. M. Spear, April 5, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Of Sleep," by J. M. Spear, April 6, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Of Propulsion," by J. M. Spear, April 7, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Of Repulsion," by J. M. Spear, April 7, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Of Adjustments," by J. M. Spear [2 copies, one in Spear's hand], April 7, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Of Reconstruction, etc.," [J. M. Spear], April 9, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "Of Miniatures," by J. M. Spear, April 9, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "Of the Constructive Mental Faculties," by J. M. Spear, April 9, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Of the Hand," [J. M. Spear], April 9, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "Of Practical Steps to be Taken by the Implementist," by J. M. Spear, April 12, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "Of Combination and Union," by J. M. Spear, April 12, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "Of the Mechanism of the New State" [T. S. Sheldon], April 26, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Communication to the Arranger given by Robert Rantoul, Messenger, April 27, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "Of Models," by T. S. Sheldon, May 4, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Of Order," by T. S. Sheldon, May 7, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Of the Road to Wealth," by J. M. Spear, July 3, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "Of the Human Mind," by T. S. Sheldon, July 22, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "To the Divinationist," by J. M. Spear, signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], July 28, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - John M. Spear to My Brother [Sheldon], July 30, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Communicator [J. M. Spear] to My Brother [Sheldon], July 30, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Agreement signed by Mary Gardner, written by J. M. Spear, August 1, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - List of papers to be transmitted, written by J. M. Spear, August 12, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "Of the Inventor, Artisan, Builder," by J. M. Spear, August 21, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Arranger to Brother Harmonizer, August 26, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Meeting minutes of the Sacred Order of Unionists, September 28, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Indenture, Alpheus Cowles to John Orvis, September 30, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Scope and Content Notes
    Cover: Received for record on October 8, 1861
  - "Of Harmonic Life" [J. M. Spear], October 28, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Note signed Eureka, [October 28, 1861] (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Schedule of personal property delivered by Horace Fenton to the Sacred Order of Unionists, November 19, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Indenture, Horace Fenton to the Sacred Order of Unionists, signed by Fenton and Sheldon, November 19, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "Position and Obligations of the Commercial Agent," signed by Sheldon and Orvis, January 1, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - "Of National Concentration," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], January 3, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "Of Sacred Matrimony" [T. S. Sheldon], March 19, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Copy of agreement Between John Orvis and T. S. Sheldon, April 1, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Report of Matron at Mt. Alpheus from December 17, 1861-May 1, 1862, May 9, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Address to the President of the General Assembly by J. M. Spear, May 12, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - T. S. Sheldon to Bro Orvis, with cash accounts from March 1 to June 1, 1862, June 3, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - C. F. Doane to T. S. Sheldon, June 5, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - C. F. Doane to T. S. Sheldon, August 1, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - "Things To Be Done in the Modelic Years," by Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], August 22, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Untitled, by J. M. Spear, September 16, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Financial Report of Communicative and Educational Departments of the Sacred Order of Unionists for the third quarter of 1862, October 1, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Financial Reports from Mt. Alpheus for May-October 1862 by C. F. Doane (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Receipts and Expenses at Mt. Alpheus, November 1862 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Report of Expenditures at Mt. Alpheus, December 2, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - "To the Omniarch," by J. M. Spear, January 5, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - "Conditions Requisite to Proper Wealth," by J. M. Spear, January 17, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - "Of Business Management," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], January 24, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - "Of A Real Estate Association," by J. M. Spear, January 17, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - John Orvis to the head of the General Assembly, February 2, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Proclamation of the Omniarch Dissolution of the Sacred Order of Unionists, by John Orvis, February 2, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - John Orvis to the head of the Assembly, February 2, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - John Orvis to the head of the Assembly, February 4, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - John Orvis to the head of the General Assembly, February 12, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - "Of New York" and "Of Philadelphia," by J. M. Spear, February 21, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Plan of Business Action for the Month of March 1863, by J. M. Spear, February 22, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - "Thoughts for the Consideration of the More Immediate (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Reading of J. N. Stebbins by J. M. Spear, March 1863 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Community Proposition to Orvis, Boyd and Company by J. M. Spear, February 2, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - "Business Action," by J. M. Spear, March 7, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - John Orvis to Brother Sheldon, March 2, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - "Methods of Action," by J. M. Spear, March 2, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - "Of Trade, its Qualities, Characteristics, Uses and Tendencies," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], March 3, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - "Of Speculations," by J. M. Spear, March 7, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - "Of Exhibitions," by J. M. Spear, March 7, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - "Of the Bodily and Mental Powers to be Used in Speculative Labors," by J. M. Spear, March 8, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - "Things to be thought of to the General Agent," by J. M. Spear, March 8, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - "Plan of Action," by J. M. Spear, ca. March 10, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - "Counsel to the Agent," J. M. Spear, March 10, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - "Counsel to the Agent of the Iron Mountains, etc." by J. M. Spear, March 11, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Counsel to the Agent (J. M. Spear), March 12, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - "Prognosis," J. M. Spear, March 12, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - "Of the Balance Faculties," by J. M. Spear, March 13, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - "Of Banks of Treasury Notes and of Other Financial Institutions," by J. M. Spear, March 13, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - "Of the Union," by J. M. Spear, March 14, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - "Methods of Action at Philadelphia," by J. M. Spear, March 20, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Of Gold and Its Uses," by J. M. Spear, March 20, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Of the Russian Iron," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], March 21, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Counsel to the Agent," by J. M. Spear, March 22, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Of Corporations," by J. M. Spear, March 22, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Prognosis," by J. M. Spear, March 22, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Of Loans and of Credit in General," by J. M. Spear, March 27, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Preparative Instructions," J. M. Spear, March 28, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Scheme of Action on the British Mind," J. M. Spear, March 28, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Of the Machine and Its Sale," by J. M. Spear, March 29, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Special Directions," J. M. Spear, March 29, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Of the Erie Railway," by J.M Spear, March 30, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Communication Received at the Western Hotel, March 31, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - T. S. Sheldon to Dear Brother, April 1, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "Business Compact," by J. M. Spear, April 1, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Instructions," by J. M. Spear, April 1, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "Questions to be --," J. M. Spear, April 4, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "Thoughts for the Serious Consideration of the Agent," by J. M. Spear, April 10, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "Scheme of Action for the Serious Consideration of the Agent," by J. M. Spear, April 11, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "Thoughts for the Consideration of the Agent," by J. M. Spear, April 15, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "Thoughts for the Consideration of the Agent," by J. M. Spear, April 16, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "Thoughts for the Consideration of the Agent," by J. M. Spear, April 19, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "Sketch of the Character of Elias Howe," by J. M. Spear, April 20, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Of the Intellectual, the Moral, Spiritual and the Religious Faculties," by J. M. Spear, April 21, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "Of the Powers, Obligations, and Limitations of the Associated Spirit World," by J. M. Spear, April 22, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "The Office of the Mediator," by J. M. Spear, April 23, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "Thoughts for Consideration of the Agent," by J. M. Spear, May 1, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Papers transmitted in connection with Dr. Redfield by J. M. Spear, May 2 and 6, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - "Basis of Negotiation," by J. M. Spear, ca. May 5, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "My Plan of Action," by J. M. Spear, May 5, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - "Thoughts for the Consideration of the Agent," by J. M. Spear, May 5, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - "Thoughts for the Consideration of the Agent," by J. M. Spear, May 7, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "Things to be Thought of by the Agent," by J. M. Spear, May 15, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - "Plan of Action on the Part of the Agent," by J. M. Spear, May 16, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - "Of Divorce, etc.," by J. M. Spear, May 17, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - "Of the New Stock Company," by J. M. Spear, May 23, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - "To the President of Commerce," by J. M. Spear, May 23, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - "Plan of Unitive Action," by J. M. Spear, May 25, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 38)